Bye-bye!
Bye-bye, Kobato!
See you Monday!
Sorry!
Again and again...
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Move it, you're gonna make me late.
Work again?
Yeah, whatever.
Good work, Kobato.
Is there anything else I can help with?
No, that's fine. You can go home now.
Part-Time Jobs
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Detective Hanato Kobato.
Wow, there's all sorts of jobs.
Part-
Time
Jobs
What are you up to with that book?
I'm finding a job! Just like Fujimoto!
What, you wanna help pay back the loan too?
Yeah!
Maybe I can get up bright and early and deliver newspapers!
A sleepyhead like you?
How about delivering pizza to people's houses?
We both know you'd just get lost.
Then maybe I could help out as a mover.
You'll stumble and break their vases.
Then what should I do?
Don't ask me!
I give up!
Ioryogi?
Good evening!
Hi?
He's torn.
The poor thing.
Sorry to bother you.
No problem.
Here, he's all fixed up.
Thank you.
No problem.
But there's something else I wanted to ask you...
Oh, you're the guy with the umbrella!
You're...
Thanks for letting me keep it so long!
Don't worry about it.
Oh, you two already know each other?
Yeah.
I'm Ueda. I run this bakery.
I'm Hanato Kobato!
Kobato lives in one of my apartments.
She usually helps out at Yomogi Nursery.
She said she was looking for a job, and I thought of your shop.
I see. We've been really busy, it'd be great if you could help out on the weekends.
At least until my hands heal.
They're all messed up.
What happened to you?
I was being an airhead.
She hurt herself just recently.
Are you okay?
Yeah, but when it gets busy he has a lot of trouble now.
I hope you can help out, Kobato.
Of course. I'll be glad to, boss!
And, uh...
I'm Ohmura Yumi. Pleased to meet you, Kobato.
Do your best, Kobato!
Okay!
I'm done changing!
Great, you got the uniform perfect.
Now what do I do?
Well... First, when a customer comes, say "Welcome!".
Welcome!
Like that.
Okay!
After that, listen to their order, and put their cake into a box.
One of these?
I'll run the register, so you get their money...
Then I say "Thank you!?
Yeah, that's it!
Welcome!
Wanna give it a shot?
Sure!
Hmm. I'd like some shortcake and a montblanc. And...
Shortcake and montblanc.
Not cheesecake, apple pie.
Cheese, apple...
And a lemon tart!
Lemon? Um...
And a creampuff, please.
Er, um...
Shortcake and a montblanc...
Then apple pie, a lemon tart, and a creampuff.
You're great, Yumi!
Put them in the box, Kobato.
Okay!
Hmm, shortcake-
Sorry!
Calm down and get another piece.
Okay...
Are you okay, Kobato?
Yeah.
Then a montblanc, and...
Apple pie, a lemon tart, and a creampuff.
Here it is!
All right, last but not least...
Thank you!
Why, aren't you enthusiastic. You're welcome.
Is that okay?
Yeah, you just need a little more practice.
Welcome!
Huh?
Kobato!
It's Marina and her mommy!
Welcome!
Hello.
Kobato's a baker!
Yeah, I'm a baker today!
That's nice!
What kind of cake would you like?
We came to pick up my birthday cake today.
It's your birthday? Congratulations!
Box that up for them.
Okay!
I'll let you take care of it.
Sure.
Here! Sorry to keep you waiting!
Thanks, Kobato.
Thank you!
See you!
Huh?
What's wrong?
Happy Birthday, Marina
Why's this still here?
Maybe we gave them the wrong-
I'll go catch Marina!
Marina!
Kobato, are you okay?
Yeah...
Welcome!
I'll have one of these, and one of those.
Okay!
She'd like a montblanc and some cheesecake.
Sorry!
I'm worn out.
Good work, Kobato.
You too.
Here, a gift.
Thank you.
Ioryogi will love it.
Io-?
He says to pretend he's a stuffed animal!
See you tomorrow.
Really? Tomorrow too?
Of course.
Yumi, you can go home too.
What about cleanup?
I've got it.
You're hurt, don't overwork yourself.
Okay.
I'm leaving, boss.
I'll be leaving now!
Okay. Good work.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
You look worried, Yumi.
It's about the boss.
The boss?
Something's bothering him.
I tried asking him, but he said it was nothing.
Really?
The store's doing well.
Then what could he be worried about?
Maybe it's a loan?
Yomogi Nursery is having a lot of trouble with them.
Don't tell me that's why you got a job here, Kobato.
Yes!
Wow, you're amazing.
No, Miss Sayaka and Fujimoto are amazing.
That's why I want to help them out.
I want to help the boss out, too.
Wow, this ain't half bad!
Wanting to help someone but not being able to must hurt.
I'll find out what's bothering the boss!
Sure, whatever. Just don't say something dumb and get yourself fired.
If you do, I won't get any more of this cake.
I guess you could get another job, though.
Like at a sushi bar!
Or a steakhouse!
Or sit-down Chinese!
Kobato! What's your next job?
I'm staying at the bakery!
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato!
Can you put these cookies on the shelf?
Sure.
All right, you're in charge up here.
Did he just sigh looking at me?
Did he?
I wonder why...
Is the boss worried about me?
I'll ask him what it is!
Leave it to me!
Really? Can you do it casually?
Yeah! I'll try my best!
Excuse me...
Kobato?
Well, um...
I had something I wanted to ask you casually!
Kobato...
What is it?
Is there something you're worried about?
No, I'm fine. Nothing at all.
But Yumi said you keep getting lost in thought, and acting like you want to say something.
It's weird!
It's nothing she needs to worry about.
Is what he said.
Putting it that way just makes it seem weirder.
Welcome!
Huh? Kobato?
Miss Sayaka!
What are you doing here?
She's helping out until I'm all healed.
I see.
Would you like a cake?
I was going to visit Chitose, and thought I'd buy a gift.
I haven't had a cake from Tirol in a while.
That's right, you used to order for your husband's birthday.
Miss Sayaka's husband?
Women normally have those when they get married, yeah.
But I've never met him.
They must have split up.
Miss Sayaka seemed so lonely...
Don't bother her about it.
Why not?
She probably doesn't want to talk about it.
Weren't you just trying to keep it hush-hush that you got a job to help the nursery?
Everyone has stuff they don't want to talk about.
Even the boss at Tirol?
But if Yumi wants to know...
What do I do then?
Check it out on the down-low.
Not that you're any good at that .
But I'll try my best!
Thank you.
Well, I guess this counts.
Oh, Kobato!
What are you doing?
I'm checking things out on the down-low.
Wow, you're just like a detective!
A detective?
This is what a detective is?
Yeah.
That's it.
They check things out.
Prove motives and alibis.
And they search and ask around.
And tail people.
That's so cool!
Let us help out!
No, detectives work alone!
That's right!
You've got this all wrong...
Thank you.
Excuse me!
I'm a detective today.
A detective?
Have you noticed anything strange around Tirol?
Not reall.
Did something happen?
Yes! The boss is worried about something!
The boss is...
Worried?
Do you have any ideas?
No, nothing-
At al?
Tirol's cakes are pretty popular. Maybe it's something other than work?
Really?
Thanks!
See you.
This ain't gonna cut it. I'll use my own informants.
Informants?
What!?
No way I can do that!
You're a tough nut to crack, Genko.
If you came to sweet-talk someone, you're at the wrong place!
Fine, I'll just take this and leave.
You just came to eat my baumkuchen, didn't you!
Looks like you figured me out.
What!?
See ya.
Good job.
Yumi!
Kobato?
Good evening!
What are you doing?
I'm a detective!
So far I've found out that Tirol's cakes are popular,
and that he might be worried about things other than work.
I learned that he's always giving chocolate to the kids,
asking how people are feeling, and that everyone loves his cakes, too.
And he gave me a chocolate!
The boss is so kind to everyone!
Okay, now let's to tail him.
That's enough, Kobato. Let's just go home.
But...
Huh?
Is he waiting for someone?
We can't follow him in there, but...
Someone's coming!
I wonder who that is.
You don't know her?
Not at all.
Maybe it's a date? Is that why he didn't tell me?
What do I do, Kobato!?
Calm down, Yumi!
He's gonna see us!
Yumi?
Yumi!
Wait!
Boss?
Kobato!
Owwww...
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Never mind that, who were you meeting before?
To be honest, it was an interview.
For a new employee.
A new employee? Why?
Kobato, you're around on the weekends,
but I haven't been able to give Yumi time off in so long.
Time off?
I thought she was tired out, and that might be how she got hurt.
Boss... That's what you were worried about?
Yeah. You work so hard...
I thought I had to do something to recognize that.
But I enjoy working with you! I don't want time off!
Just seeing everyone overjoyed at Tirol's cakes every day...
Just being with you is enjoyable!
And I got hurt by...
Um...
Wow, it's so cute!
Yumi, you made this?
Yes.
I got hurt ditzing out while practicing making cakes.
Pieces
of
Cake
I'm sorry I didn't tell you I was studying so I could help out.
Shall we give it a try?
Sure!
It's tasty.
Really?
Once the new girl is here, I'll make time for us to work on making cakes together.
Yes!
What, you figured something out?
Yes! Detective Kobato cracked the case!
The boss wanted to give Yumi time off,
but Yumi wanted to do more for the boss.
It was a wonderful case where they realized each other's feelings!
Oh well. I got more baumkuchen anyway.
That's not from Tirol, is it?
And you've brought some home before..
Does it have anything to do with your informants?
Oh, right! Your score this time...
I ate your cake, so I'll take it easy on you. 100 points!
Really!?
Fujimoto!
What?
I have something for you!
A chocolate I got from work!
Work? You?
I'll try my best!
So please, take a little off time and focus on school.
It doesn't matter if you try, it probably won't do any good.
Meanie!
Hey...
Don't kill yourself overdoing it.
Wow, you're worried about me?
No way.
Thanks so much!
Why don't you just do something about the scribbles on your face!
But he wrote 100 points!
He scribbled 100 points.
Wrong! Fujimoto, you're a meanie! 50 points!
What are you going on about?
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
...Silver Eyes.
Next episode